## Deivid William Rodrigues dos Santos

Bleicherstrasse 12 • Luzern, Switzerland • <u>Deivid.w.santos@gmail.com</u> +41 78 421 51 66

https://deividwsantoss.github.io/portfolio/



#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Passionate about technology and a self-motivated professional with over 5 years of experience as a System Analyst / test engineer in a multinational company located in Brazil. I am Highly organized, self-motivated, and diligent professional with collaborative mindset and good interpersonal relationship.

- Core Competencies -

- Software testing Life cycle
- · Agile Methodologies
- Database Administration

- Troubleshooter
- Positive Teamwork and Collaboration
- System Administration

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Petrolink Services .**, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil *Team leader Senior System Analyst* (2015 – 2017)

Responsible for managing activities related to the Software for the branch in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Working directly with the Director and Sales Department.

**Petrolink Services.**, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil *Pleno System Analyst – Test Engineer (2013 – 2015)* 

Monitoring, maintaining, and troubleshooting of Real-time data-streams (WITS, WITSML and XML). User Access support, Data Converters and Aggregators Support in Onshore and Offshore Rigs Ensuring proper data mapping and units of measurement of all incoming Real-time data. 2<sup>nd</sup> and 3<sup>rd</sup> level support of Real-time related issues, including server issues, connection issues, internal issues, and contractor issues. Managing Databases (SQL SERVER), providing reports based on Director / Operations Reguest.

- Provide improvements to the System according to meetings with clients
- Report issues
- Test Case creation / Test Execution
  - Analyzing requirements/use cases/user stories from the Product Owner.
  - Participating in preparing test plans and test scenarios.
  - Preparing Test Cases for modules, integration, and system testing.
  - Preparing Test Data for tests.
  - Preparing Test Environment to execute the test cases.
  - Analyzing the Test Cases prepared by other team members.
  - Executing the Test Cases.
  - Defect Tracking.

- Use existing tools and frameworks to build/script test conditions for automating tests.
- Execute test cases and publish result analysis.
- Participate in troubleshooting issues alongside other technical and operational teams.
- System Administrator

Training and Specialization on Real-Time Software done in Houston – Texas. Management Software used: JIRA

# **Petrolink Services.,** Rio de Janeiro, Brazil *Junior System Analyst* (2012 – 2013)

Monitor the data flow within the client databases on the Petrolink system.

To present data to the highest standard (to enable all authorized account holders to utilize the information).

Processing of this client data will be directed by the DTL through the tracker or similar system. Each item of client data must be processed according to the procedure.

First independent client data verification and quality control check of the distribution work, i.e., first buddy procedure.

Staying abreast of client activities, both at wellsite and onshore.

Investigating new processing techniques with bespoke packages, specially log plot software.

Providing first line customer support performed by the Operations Centre.

Monitoring of the Petrolink Infrastructure, servers, and websites, reporting to GIS.

To be available for a fair share of reserve call-out duty.

#### Mundivox Telecomunications, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Intern Technical Support (2011 – 2012)

Mundivox is a telecommunications operator and provider

Integrated solutions for voice services and data aimed at the corporate market.

### **EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS**

**Durham College / UOIT,** Ontario, Canada Computer Programming Analyst 2021

**Linux Academy** - LPI Linux Essentials 2016-03-28

Infnet – Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012 – Microsoft Partner
Administering Microsoft SQL Server 2012 – Microsoft Partner
Implementing a Data Warehouse with Microsoft SQL Server – Microsoft Partner

**TreinaWeb Courses –** Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Basic C# programming SQL Server Database Administrator

**UDEMY** – Online Courses MCSA SQL Server 2019 Database Administration ISTQB Foundation Level certification training for exam 2021

Catholic University of Pernambuco, Pernambuco, Brazil Computer Science 2007-2010

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### Good Knowledge on Programming:

WPF, Windows forms, C# (.NET Core/.NET Framework/ASP.NET Core/Entity Framework Core), C++, SQL, HTML5/CSS3, PHP, Java (Spring Framework, Hibernate), JavaScript, Node.js, jQuery, JSON, Ajax, AngularJS, Mainframe Programming – Cobol

IDEs: Visual Studio, Visual Code, INTELLIJ IDEA, NetBeans, Eclipse, DEV-C++

Databases: SQL Server, POSTGREE SQL, MySQL, Mango DB, Oracle

Operational Systems: Linux, Windows

As well Good knowledge on - GitHub, Bash, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes

**Experienced with JIRA Management System.** 

## **LANGUAGES**

Portuguese: Mother Language

English: FluentSpanish: BasicDeutsch: Basic

Deivid William Rodrigues dos Santos 03.23.2021